sharebuilder.com 2017-07-11

# Capital One Investing

## Privacy

We know your privacy is valuable (that’s why we never peek over the fence into your backyard). To learn how we collect, share and protect your information after you’ve applied for or obtained a consumer product or service from us, please download our [Privacy & Opt-Out Notice](https://content.capitaloneinvesting.com/mgdcon/core/agreements/CapitalOnePrivacyPolicy.pdf).

### Privacy Settings

Looking to update your Privacy Settings? Sign in and go to our [Profile & Settings](https://www.capitaloneinvesting.com/main/account/profile/personalinfo.aspx) page. You can update your Communications and Sharing Preferences under the Privacy Settings section.

### Maintenance of Accurate Information

We work hard to make sure the personal information we maintain about you is accurate, complete, and up to date. Something not right? Sign in and go to our [Profile & Settings](https://www.capitaloneinvesting.com/main/account/profile/personalinfo.aspx) page to update your personal information, or if you need to, get ahold of one of our friendly Customer Service Associates by using the Help link at the top of the page.

## Our Social Security Number Protections

Capital One protects your Social Security Number. Our policies and procedures: 

  1. Protect the confidentiality of Social Security numbers;
  2. Prohibit the unlawful disclosure of Social Security numbers; and
  3. Limit access to Social Security numbers to employees or others with legitimate business purposes.

These safeguards apply to all Social Security numbers collected through any channel or retained in any way by Capital One in connection with customer, employee, or other relationships. Individuals applying for or obtaining a product or service from us to be used primarily for personal, family, or household purposes may obtain more information by reviewing the [Privacy & Opt-Out Notice](https://content.capitaloneinvesting.com/mgdcon/core/agreements/CapitalOnePrivacyPolicy.pdf).

## Our Online & Mobile Privacy Statement

Our Online & Mobile Privacy Statement describes our mobile privacy practices and how they apply to you when visiting our website, mobile app, or social media pages.

### Information We Collect

"Contact Information" – this means your name, address, telephone number, employment status, fax number, and email address.

"Personal Nonpublic Information" – we're talking about personally identifiable information about you and transactions in your account, including your Social Security number, account numbers, and information about your assets, accounts, transactions, and tax status.

"Online/Mobile Activity Data" – this refers to your IP address, browser type and language, and your display/screen settings. It also relates to data about how you use or interact with our website and mobile advertisements, data about your mobile device, advertising identifiers, geolocation data, social media preferences and other social media data, and other data that may be aggregated and/or de-identified (information that doesn't identify individual Consumers/Customers).

## How We Collect Information

### When You Use or Visit Our Website

We may collect information about you when you browse our website or use our online services. We may collect Personal Information when you voluntarily provide it to us through forms on our website or in our mobile applications (i.e. surveys, account applications, contest entries, and sign in pages for online or mobile investing).

We may also use cookies and other online tracking devices such as pixel tags and clear GIFs (also known as web beacons) to collect Online/Mobile Activity Data about you depending on your browser settings. "Cookies" are bite sized pieces of data that a website can send to your browser and store on your computer. Our cookies don't collect or contain personal information about you or compromise the confidentiality of your personal information. A Web beacon is a small string of software code that represents a graphic image on a website or email.

Our system automatically gathers information about the areas you visit on our sites and about the links you may select from within our site to other areas of the Internet or elsewhere online. We use this information to understand how our users as a group use the services and resources on our sites. This way we know which areas of our sites are favorites of our users, which areas need improvement, and what technologies are being used so that we can continually improve our sites. We link this usage information to Contact Information or Personal Nonpublic Information in order to securely verify your identity, to personalize aspects of your experience on our web sites, to better understand which information or services are of greater value to our customers, and to send follow-up communications regarding our products and services to website visitors.

We may also partner with third parties to deliver advertisements and monitor activities on our own website and other websites. Our partners may use cookies, web beacons, and/or other monitoring technologies to compile statistics about website visitors.

### When You Use Our Mobile Apps

Additionally, we may collect Online/Mobile Activity Data when you access our mobile applications or use the browser on your mobile device to access our website. For example, we may determine device type or mobile OS data from your device.

### When You Use Our Social Media Pages

We have official pages on social media websites such as Facebook®, Twitter®, and YouTube that enable Consumers and Customers to discuss their experiences with our products and services. We may also partner with companies that operate social media websites through which you may interact with us. When you interact with us on social media websites we may collect information such as your likes, interests, feedback, and preferences. When you interact with our partners, you are subject to their terms of use and privacy policies. We may collect information from our social media partners, but only if you choose to share with them and they, in turn, share such information with us. Never include sensitive personal, financial or other confidential information such as your Social Security number, account number, phone number, mailing address, or email address when posting or commenting online. Any posts you make on our official social media pages–including posts that contain pictures, comments, suggestions, opinions, complaints, or Personal Information–are available to others who use those pages and are subject to the terms of use and privacy policies of the companies that operate the websites on which they appear. Please refer to the policies of those companies to better understand your rights and obligations with regards to such posts. You are also subject to this Statement and our social media guidelines when you visit our official social media pages.

## How We Use Information

We may use Contact Information, Personal Information, and Online/Mobile Activity Data we have collected for a variety of reasons. For example, we may use this type of data: 

  * to enable you to apply for and open Capital One products or services
  * to enable you to use online tools or perform certain online transactions
  * to service and manage your accounts including responding or updating you on questions or to contact you about your accounts
  * to offer you special products and services and deliver advertisements to you in the form of banner ads, splash ads (ads that appear as you sign in or sign out of viewing your online accounts) or promotions based on your location
  * to verify your identity and/or location to allow access to your accounts, conduct online transactions and assist us in taking data security precautions and to engage in fraud prevention/detection
  * for business purposes, including data analysis, to improve, personalize, optimize your website browsing and mobile application experiences by examining which parts of our website you visit, which aspect of our mobile applications you find most useful, and to improve existing or develop new products and services
  * to comply with federal, state or local laws; civil, criminal or regulatory investigations; or other legal requirements
  * to share with companies within the Capital One family, and with trusted third parties who are contractually obligated to keep such information confidential and to use it only to provide the services we have asked them to perform (For a description of how Capital One may share information collected from consumers who have applied for or obtained a product or service from us, please refer to the [Privacy & Opt-Out Notice](https://content.capitaloneinvesting.com/mgdcon/core/agreements/CapitalOnePrivacyPolicy.pdf).)

**Adobe Analytics** is a company we use to track and analyze the use of our site. Capital One Investing℠ and Adobe record user sessions and store aggregated technical and navigational data. The recorded sessions are used to service and maintain accounts, and respond to customer inquiries. We own this recorded and aggregated data and will not share personal non-public information with third parties. The aggregated data is analyzed by Capital One Investing and the results are used to improve web site design and functionality in order to deliver better products and services.

Although we don't allow Adobe Analytics to capture or transmit any detailed transactional information, banking information, credit card information or other personal financial information, the data collected does include the nature of the service used (for example, whether you placed a trade, but not details about the trade), your email address and a unique customer identifier that Capital One Investing (not Adobe Analytics) can use to associate the data collected with individual customers.

## Managing Your Online & Mobile Preferences

You provide Personal Information to us on a voluntary basis and are not required to provide it in order to browse our websites. If you provide us with Personal Information to obtain a product or service, our [Privacy & Opt-Out Notice](https://content.capitaloneinvesting.com/mgdcon/core/agreements/CapitalOnePrivacyPolicy.pdf) will govern how we share your Personal Information with our affiliates and third parties and will enable you to opt out of certain types of sharing.

### Online Tracking & Advertising on our Sites or Apps

As you access our online services over time, cookies and similar technologies such as web beacons allow us to collect information such as browser type, pages visited, preferences, and your relationship with us. Capital One may customize content and advertisements for our products and services on the websites or mobile apps we own. In order to make the content and advertising as informative and useful as possible, we may use information about your relationship with us (such as types of accounts, transactional information, or the state in which you bank). Currently, for online advertising purposes, our website does not respond to browser "do not track" signals, but these signals may be used for fraud prevention. However, if you choose, you can set your website browser to inform you when cookies are sent or you may choose not to accept cookies. Your decision not to accept cookies would limit access to some of the services and offers that are available on our website. For example, your device may not be recognized when you visit our website and, if you are an online banking customer, you may need to answer challenge questions each time you log on. You also may not receive advertising or other offers from us that may be of interest to you.

### Mobile Devices

Some mobile devices come with a non-permanent advertising identifier or ID, which gives companies the ability to serve targeted ads to a specific mobile device. In many cases, you can turn off mobile device ad tracking or reset the advertising identifier at any time within your mobile device privacy settings. You may also choose to turn off location tracking on your mobile device. By turning off ad tracking or location tracking on your mobile device, you may still see the same number of ads as before, but they may be less relevant because they will not be based on your interests.

### Behavioral Advertising on Third Party Sites

Certain Capital One partners may use unique cookies to collect Mobile/Online Activity Data in order to advertise Capital One products and services that may be of interest to you. Our partners are subject to their own privacy policies. If you prefer to not have our partners display such advertisements to you, you may opt out by visiting the Digital Advertising Alliance's [opt out page](https://www.aboutads.info/choices) or by clicking on the AdChoices icon in an advertisement ( ) and following the instructions. You may also opt out of receiving behavioral ads from many sites through the Network Advertising Initiative's (NAI) [Opt-Out Tool](https://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/?partnerId=1/) or other tools provided by the publishing platform. Opting out relies on information in the unique cookies placed on your web browser by our partners, so if you delete cookies, use a different device, or change web browsers, you may need to opt out again. Additionally, we may partner with websites like Google and Yahoo to display ads to you based on search terms you use on those websites. Please review the privacy policies of those websites for instructions on how to limit these ads.

Please note that you may still receive general online advertising from Capital One even after you adjust your ad preferences with certain web search engines or opt out of online advertising through AdChoices or the NAI tool. However, such advertising will not be based on Online/Mobile Activity Data or search term information.

You can [deactivate](http://data.capitaloneinvesting.com/optout.html) our ability to analyze your browsing behavior through the use of Adobe Analytics' web analytics services.

### Email

If we send you an email advertisement, it will include instructions on how to opt out of receiving such emails in the future. If you are a Customer and you elect to opt out of receiving email advertisements, we may still send you emails about your account relationships with us. To opt out of receiving email advertisements, you may submit your request at our [Profile & Settings](https://www.capitaloneinvesting.com/main/account/profile/personalinfo.aspx) page. If your name was previously selected for any of our upcoming email offers, it is possible for you to receive information from us up to 10 business days after your request has been submitted.

If you receive an email that claims to be from us but you are not sure, or if you think it is suspicious, do not click on any of the links in the email. Instead, forward it to us at [abuse@capitalone.com](mailto:abuse@capitalone.com) then delete it. For more email security tips, see the [Capital One Fraud and Identity Theft page](http://www.capitalone.com/identity-protection/security/)

### Protecting Children's Online Privacy

We encourage protection of children's information on the internet. We don't intentionally collect personal information from children under 13 on our website without first obtaining consent from their parents or legal guardians. For more information about the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) please refer to the [FTC's website](https://www.ftc.gov/privacy/privacyinitiatives/childrens.html)

### Links

Our websites may include links to third-party websites. These third parties are not subject to this Statement or to the Capital One Privacy and Opt Out Notice. Whenever you visit a third-party website, you should review its privacy notice.

## Security

Capital One Investing takes the security of information very seriously and has established security standards and procedures to prevent unauthorized access to customer information. We use industry standard means such as physical, electronic and procedural safeguards, including data encryption and secure socket layer technology. We update and test our technology regularly to maintain and improve the protection of our customers' information. We restrict access to personal information to employees and service providers for legitimate business purposes to assist in providing services to you. Employees who violate our privacy policy are subject to disciplinary action.

We maintain Customer authentication procedures to protect your personal information and account from identity theft. These procedures are for your protection. If you suspect a website is pretending to be a Capital One website (also known as "spoofing"), don't enter personal information, just [contact us](https://www.capitaloneinvesting.com/main/help/contactus.aspx) or email [abuse@capitalone.com](mailto:abuse@capitalone.com).

### Changes to this Statement

This Statement describes Capital One's current online privacy practices. These privacy practices are subject to change at any time. This Statement is effective as of June 5, 2015.
